etcconnect.com 2019-12-31

# Electronic Theatre Controls’ Privacy, Cookie, Terms of Use, and Acceptable Use Policies

  *   * #### **_Privacy Policy_**

_Last Updated: October 22, 2019_

This Privacy Policy describes the information collected through this website “Site” and how that information is used and shared. Electronic Theatre Controls, Inc., and its affiliates, (“ETC,” “we,” “us,” or “our”) may collect or receive the types of information described below in connection with your access to and use of the Site, including your account registration on the Site and any information you may post to the site (together, “Collected Information”).

Please read this Privacy Policy and the Terms of Use carefully to understand our policies and practices regarding Collected Information and how we use and share it. By accessing, using or submitting information via this Site, you agree on behalf of yourself and any company that you represent (together, “you” and “your”) to this Privacy Policy, our Terms of Use Policy, and our Acceptable Use Policy, in addition to ETC’s use and sharing of information as discussed below. **If you do not agree with this Privacy Policy, please do not access or use this Site**.

**This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and made a part of our Terms of Use.**

###### **Changes to this Privacy Policy**

We may amend or otherwise modify this Privacy Policy at any time. All modifications will take effect immediately upon posting of the updated Privacy Policy on the Site. By accessing or using the Site after modifications are posted, you agree to those modifications. Material changes will be conspicuously posted on the Site. You are encouraged to revisit this Privacy Policy from time to time in order to review any changes that have been made. The date on which this Privacy Policy was last updated is noted at the beginning of this Privacy Policy.

    1. ###### **General**

ETC respects the privacy of all visitors to the Site. Whether you provide us with your personally identifiable information is your decision. You do not have to tell us who you are or reveal anything further about yourself to visit this Site. We collect only the information necessary to maintain a satisfactory business relationship with you or your company.

Notwithstanding the above, we may collect and use other information that may be considered personally identifiable information in some jurisdictions (such as your IP address) in order to make our website accessible to you. Such information will automatically be transmitted by your computer. Without your explicit consent, we will not use such information for any other purpose than making the Site accessible to you.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to information that we may collect through any medium other than the Site (e.g., collected offline), or to information collected by any person or entity other than us (such as a third-party website or a third-party application).

    2. ###### **Information about Electronic Theatre Controls, Inc.'s Participation in the Privacy Shield**

Electronic Theatre Controls, Inc. complies with the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the US Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and the United Kingdom to the United States in reliance on Privacy Shield. Electronic Theatre Controls, Inc. has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles in respect to such information, including the Privacy Shield Principles of Notice, Choice, Accountability for Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation, Access, and Recourse, Enforcement and Liability. If there is any conflict between the policies in this Privacy Policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Program, and to view our certification page, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>.

In compliance with the EU-US Privacy Shield Principles, Electronic Theatre Controls, Inc. commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact Electronic Theatre Controls, Inc. at:

ETC - Attention Office of General Counsel   
3031 Pleasant View Road   
Middleton, WI 53562   
USA   
Email: [privacy@etcconnect.com](mailto:privacy@etcconnect.com)

Electronic Theatre Controls, Inc. has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the EU-US Privacy Shield Principles to the BBB EU PRIVACY SHIELD, a non-profit alternative dispute resolution provider located in the United States and operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgement of your complaint or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit [www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers/](http://www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers/) for more information and to file a complaint.   

Please note that if your complaint is not resolved through these channels, under limited circumstances, a binding arbitration option may be available before a Privacy Shield Panel.

Electronic Theatre Controls, Inc. is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC).

    3. ###### **Information about Electronic Theatre Controls GmbH’s Data Protection Officer**

Pursuant to Section 38 of the German Data Protection Amendment Act, Electronic Theatre Controls GmbH has appointed the following Data Protection Officer: 

Dr. Sebastian Kraska   
Marienplatz 2   
80331 Munich   
Germany   
Email: [dpo-contact@iitr.de](mailto:dpo-contact@iitr.de)

    4. ###### **Information We Collect**

Here is the information we collect through our Site and how we use it:

      1. **Personally Identifiable Information.** In this Privacy Policy, "personally identifiable information" (PII) means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person or reasonably capable of being associated with or linked with a consumer or household, including but not limited to an individual's name, postal address, e-mail address, and phone number. You can visit the Site without sharing PII, but you will be required to provide PII in order to use certain Site features. 
        1. **MyETC**. MyETC is an added feature of this Site that allows you to customize your experience on the Site and access information for your type of membership. If you choose to open a MyETC account, we will collect the following PII from you, for the purpose(s) listed in the chart below:

**Data Collected** |  **Purpose for Collection** |  **Legitimate Grounds for Collection**  
---|---|---  
First and Last Name*  |  Set up MyETC account  |  Performance of a contract - necessary for setting up MyETC account   
Email*  |  Set up MyETC account;   
marketing purposes  |  Performance of a contract - necessary for setting up MyETC account; Consent for marketing purposes   
Country*  |  Set up MyETC account  |  Performance of a contract - necessary for setting up MyETC account   
Display name and Password*  |  Set up MyETC account  |  Performance of a contract - necessary for setting up MyETC account   
Address  |  Marketing  |  Consent   
Phone number  |  Marketing  |  Consent   
Organization  |  Marketing  |  Consent   
Occupation  |  Marketing  |  Consent   
Industry  |  Marketing  |  Consent   
  
_  
*Required to set up MyETC account_

**Use of PII for Marketing**. Marketing emails are sent via a third party, Robly Digital Marketing LLC (Robly). If you do not wish to receive promotional materials, marketing materials email offers or newsletters from us, you can opt-out of receiving such information from us (other than emails related to the completion of your registration, correction of user data, change of password and other similar communications essential to your transactions on the Site) by using the unsubscribe process at the bottom of the email, by checking the relevant box located on the form on which we collect your data, adjusting your user preferences in your MyETC account profile, if applicable, or by sending us an email stating your request to [webmaster@etcconnect.com](mailto:webmaster@etcconnect.com). 

        2. **Product Registration**. If you have opened a MyETC account, you will have the choice to register any of our products you or your organization have purchased. Registration of these products is not required. If you choose to register a product, we will collect the following PII from you, for the purpose(s) listed in the chart below:

**Data Collected** |  **Purpose for Collection** |  **Legitimate Grounds for Collection**  
---|---|---  
Company Name or Individual Name*  |  Register Product  |  Performance of a contract - necessary for registering product   
Address*  |  Register Product  |  Performance of a contract - necessary for registering product   
Phone Number*  |  Register Product  |  Performance of a contract - necessary for registering product   
  
*Required to register a product

        3. **Contacting ETC through the Site.** You may contact us via the Site, or by calling or writing to us. If you choose to contact us, we will collect the following PII from you, for the purpose(s) listed in the chart below:

**Data Collected** |  **Purpose for Collection** |  **Legitimate Grounds for Collection**  
---|---|---  
Name*  |  Respond to your inquiry  |  Performance of a contract - necessary for responding to your inquiry   
Email*  |  Respond to your inquiry  |  Performance of a contract - necessary for responding to your inquiry   
Phone Number*  |  Respond to your inquiry  |  Performance of a contract - necessary for responding to your inquiry   
  
_*Required to contact us_

        4. **ETC’s Online Community.** If you have opened a MyETC account, you may participate in ETC’s Online Community forum (the “Forum”). No additional PII is collected for participating in the Forum. Anything you post to the Forum is visible by all Forum participants and will be saved until you request deletion of your post or deletion of your entire MyETC account. We will then delete your post and/or account along with your PII within 30 days of receiving your request. You are not required to share any PII in order to post on the Forum. By posting on the Forum, you consent to the cross-border transfer of any PII you have shared; you also consent to our Terms of Use and Acceptable Use Policies.
        5. **Financial Information.** You may purchase ETC swag and other items through <https://shop.etcconnect.com/> or ( <https://shop.etcconnect.eu/> if you are located in the EU). Purchases of products or services must be made by credit or debit card. All credit and debit card information is provided directly to our PCI-compliant third-party payment processor BigCommerce. We do not directly access or handle any financial information collected via this Site. If you make a debit or credit card payment online, you will be taken to a website operated by BigCommerce, who will take your payment. Payment by credit or debit card is subject to the approval of the card issuer. We will not be liable in any way if a card issuer refuses to accept a credit or debit card for any reason. You should not communicate credit card or other payment information via email, as it is not secure. To make a purchase, the following PII will be collected from you, for the purpose(s) listed in the chart below:

**Data Collected** |  **Purpose for Collection** |  **Legitimate Grounds for Collection**  
---|---|---  
Name*  |  Place Order  |  Performance of a contract - necessary to place order   
Email*  |  Place Order  |  Performance of a contract – necessary to place order   
Company Name  |  Place Order  |  Performance of a contract – necessary to place order   
Phone Number*  |  Place Order  |  Performance of a contract – necessary to place order   
Address*  |  Place Order  |  Performance of a contract – necessary to place order   
Payment Information*  |  Place Order  |  Performance of a contract – necessary to place order   
  
_*Required to make purchase_

        6. **Online Training.** You may register for online training through the Site. If you choose to register for online training, we will collect the following PII from you through third party processor Web Courseworks, Ltd., for the purpose(s) listed in the chart below:

**Data Collected** |  **Purpose for Collection** |  **Legitimate Grounds for Collection**  
---|---|---  
Name*  |  Registration for online training  |  Performance of a contract - necessary to register for online training   
Company Name  |  Registration for online training  |  Performance of a contract - necessary to register for online training   
Phone Number*  |  Registration for online training  |  Performance of a contract - necessary to register for online training   
Address*  |  Registration for online training  |  Performance of a contract - necessary to register for online training   
Payment Information*  |  Registration for online training  |  Performance of a contract - necessary to register for online training   
  
_*Required to register for online training_

        7. **Technical Training.** You may register for technical training through the Site. If you choose to register for technical training, we will collect the following PII from you through third party processor Cvent, for the purpose(s) listed in the chart below:

**Data Collected** |  **Purpose for Collection** |  **Legitimate Grounds for Collection**  
---|---|---  
Name*  |  Registration for technical training  |  Performance of a contract - necessary to register for technical training   
Company Name/Organization   
/School*  |  Registration for technical training  |  Performance of a contract - necessary to register for technical training   
Email Address*  |  Registration for technical training;   
marketing purposes**  |  Performance of a contract - necessary to register for technical training; consent for marketing purposes   
Phone Number*  |  Registration for technical training  |  Performance of a contract - necessary to register for technical training   
Address*  |  Registration for technical training  |  Performance of a contract - necessary to register for technical training   
Payment Information*  |  Registration for technical training  |  Performance of a contract - necessary to register for technical training   
  
_*Required to register for technical training_

_**Marketing emails are sent via a third party, Robly._

        8. **Conferences Registration.** You may register for ETC conferences through the Site. If you choose to register for an ETC conference, we will collect the following PII from you through third party processor Cvent, for the purpose(s) listed in the chart below:

**Data Collected** |  **Purpose for Collection** |  **Legitimate Grounds for Collection**  
---|---|---  
Name*  |  Registration for conference  |  Performance of a contract - necessary to register for conference   
Company*  |  Registration for conference  |  Performance of a contract - necessary to register for conference   
Job title  |  Registration for conference  |  Performance of a contract - necessary to register for conference   
Email Address*  |  Registration for conference;   
marketing purposes**  |  Performance of a contract - necessary to register for conference; consent for marketing purposes   
Phone Number work*   
and mobile  |  Registration for conference  |  Performance of a contract - necessary to register for conference   
Address*  |  Registration for conference  |  Performance of a contract - necessary to register for conference   
Payment Information*  |  Registration for conference  |  Performance of a contract - necessary to register for conference   
  
_*Required to register for conference_

_**Marketing emails are sent via a third party, Robly._

#####  __

        9. **Support.etcconnect.com.** ETC offers support.etcconnect.com as an additional support tool for our end users. If you choose to access this support site while logged into your MyETC account, the support site will keep track of the pages you view for thirty days through third party administrator MindTouch. ETC may use this information to tailor the support site’s content in order to better serve our end users. If you do not want your navigation of the support site to be tracked, please sign out of your MyETC account before navigating the support site. Please note, some content on the support site will not be available to you if you are not logged into your MyETC account. 

If you choose to stay logged into your MyETC account while navigating the support site, the following PII will be collect from you through third party administrator MindTouch, for the purpose(s) listed in the chart below: 

**Data Collected** | **Purpose for Collection** | **Legitimate Grounds for Collection**  
---|---|---  
Navigation of support site | Tailor support site’s content | Legitimate interest of ETC  
      2. ###### **Other Information**

When you access and interact with the Site, we will make temporary use of other information in addition to the PII mentioned above as technically necessary in order to make the Site accessible to you, including the IP address of the device you are using to access the Site. Such information will automatically be transmitted by your computer. Without your explicit consent, we will not use such information for any other purpose than making the website accessible to you. In addition, we will destroy such information after seven days.

We may also collect other information in addition to the PII mentioned above about those visits. For example, our servers may receive and record information about your computer, device, and browser, including potentially the IP address, browser type, and other software or hardware information. This information is never used to identify you personally and never combined with other personal data such as PII stored in your MyETC account or otherwise sent to us through our website. Such information includes the following:

      1. **Usage Details and IP Address.** As you navigate through this Site, details of your visits to this Site, including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, logs, the resources that you access, and information about your computer and internet connection, including your truncated IP address, operating system and browser type may be automatically transmitted by your computer. We may use this information for system administration and access to the Site.
      2. **Cookies.** "Cookies" are pieces of information that a website sends to your computer while you are viewing a website. To see our Cookie Policy, click here.
      3. **Web beacons**. "Web beacons" are electronic images, tags or scripts that allow a website to access cookies and help track general usage patterns of visitors to a website. Web beacons can recognize certain types of information, such as cookies, time and date of a page view and a description of the page where the Web beacon is placed. We may use Web beacons to compile information regarding use of this Site.
    5. **Profiling.** We will not use your PII for decisions based solely on automated processing if the decision produces legal effects concerning you or significantly affects you, unless you gave your explicit consent for this processing. 
    6. **Security.** We are committed to ensuring that your personal data is secure. In order to prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, we have put in place appropriate technical and organizational measures to safeguard and secure the personal data we process. Although we use reasonable security measures to help protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of information under our control, we cannot ensure or guarantee that loss, misuse, or alteration of your personally identifiable information or other Collected Information will not occur. If, despite all our efforts, a data breach does occur, we shall take all reasonable steps to limit the damage. In case of a data breach which is likely to result in a high risk, and depending on the circumstances, we will inform you about remedial actions to prevent any further damage when required under applicable law. We will also inform the relevant supervisory authority or authorities without undue delay, when required under applicable law.
    7. **Disclosure of PII.** We will only disclose PII to our affiliated companies, agents, and/or subcontractors for the purposes identified above, where necessary. In such cases, the agent or subcontractor will be obligated to use that PII in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy. We will not sell, distribute or lease your PII to third parties unless we have your permission or are required to do so by law. We may disclose your PII to the extent that it is required to do so by applicable law, in connection with any legal proceedings or prospective legal proceedings, and in order to establish, exercise, or defend our legal rights. 

We may be required to release personal data of EU individuals in response to lawful requests from public authorities including to meet national security and law enforcement requirements.

    8. **Aggregation and De-Personalization (Pseudonymisation).** We may take your PII, make it non-personally identifiable and combine it with other Collected Information about other individuals. Such aggregated information describes users as a group but does not reveal the identity of individual users. We may use and disclose to third parties such aggregate or de-personalized information in any manner and without notice or compensation to you.
    9. **Business Transfers.** We specifically and expressly reserve the right to disclose, lease, sell, assign and transfer Collected Information (including your PII) to the successor or acquiring entity in the event of or in connection with a Business Transfer. A "Business Transfer" means a sale, acquisition, merger, consolidation, reorganization, bankruptcy or other corporate change of control involving us, regardless of whether the Business Transfer relates to a part or a whole of our business. Before we disclose your PII in the context of a Business Transfer, we will notify you and give you a reasonable time period to object to such transfer. That successor or acquiring entity will be bound by this Privacy Policy as it applies to that information. Nothing in this Privacy Policy is intended to interfere with our ability to transfer all or part of our business, equity, and/or assets (including this Site) to an affiliate or independent third party at any time, for any purpose, without any limitation, without notice, any without any compensation to you, whatsoever.
    10. **Third Party Transfers.** Under certain circumstances, we may remain liable for the acts of our third-party agents or service providers who perform services on our behalf for their handling of EU Personal Data that we transfer to them.
    11. **Retention of PII.** We will retain your PII while your MyETC account is still active. You may contact us as instructed below to request your MyETC account be deleted. We will then delete your account along with your PII within 30 days of receiving your request. If you place an order through the ETC Swag Store, we will have to store the PII relating to such order for at least as long as necessary to fulfil the order and as long as necessary for compliance with statutory tax and accounting requirements in accordance with our Record Retention Policy, even if you do not have a MyETC account or if your MyETC account has meanwhile been deleted. Please contact the relevant third party for information regarding data retention collected through that third party.
    12. **User Generated Content.** You are responsible for any content, including PII that you create, post, or otherwise submit to be published or displayed (“posted”) on this Site ("User Generated Content"). Your User Generated Content is posted on and transmitted to other users of this Site at your own risk. We cannot control the actions of other users of this Site with whom you may choose to share your User Generated Content. As a result, we cannot and do not guarantee that your User Generated Content will not be viewed by unauthorized persons. You understand and acknowledge that, even after removal, copies of User Generated Content may remain viewable in cached and archived pages, or might have been copied or stored by other Site users. For information on submitting User Generated Content, please review our Terms of Use and Acceptable Use Policies. We may use and disclose User Generated Content, excluding components that consist of PII, in any manner and with any person. 
    13. **Information You Disclose to Third Parties.** You may be presented with an opportunity to receive information and/or marketing offers from third parties as a result of your access to or use of this Site. This Privacy Policy does not apply to such information. All information you disclose to such third parties will be subject to the privacy policies and practices of such third parties, as applicable. We will not have access to any information you choose to disclose to such third parties. We are not responsible for the privacy policies or practices of any third party. You should review the privacy policies and practices of each third party prior to disclosing information to them.
    14. **Access by Children.** The Site is not directed at children under 16 years of age. You must be at least 16 years of age to register with or use this Site. We do not knowingly collect or use information from children under 16 through the Site. If you are under 16 years of age, do not send any information about yourself to us or otherwise enter any information about yourself on this Site, including your name, address, telephone number or e-mail address. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 16 years of age, please contact us at [privacy@etcconnect.com](mailto:privacy@etcconnect.com).
    15. **Site Access From Outside the United States.** This Site is operated in the United States. If you are located in the European Union, Canada or elsewhere outside of the United States please be aware that Collected Information will be transferred to, stored, and processed in the United States. If you open a MyETC Account or post to the Forum, you acknowledge that your data will be processed in the United States.
    16. **Right to Access Correct and Delete, Withdraw Consent, Restrict, and Object to, Processing Your PII.** If you have created a MyETC account through this Site, then you have the right to access, review, and update your PII by logging into this Site, visiting your account profile page and making changes, including submitting a request to delete your account information. 

You also have the right to request: the categories of, and specific pieces of, personal information we have collected about you, if any; the categories of sources from which we collected this personal information, if any; the business or commercial purpose for which we collected this personal information, if any; and the categories of third parties with whom we have shared this personal information, if any. 

You also have the right to request access details of any PII which we hold about you, to restrict or object to our processing of your PII, and to request we delete any pieces of personal information we have on you, if any. 

**We do not sell any PII.** We may disclose PII to a third party for a business purpose, as detailed in this Privacy Policy under Section 4 – Information We Collect. 

Where you have given us consent to process your PII, you may withdraw this consent at any time. 

If you have questions or concerns about our privacy practices or this Privacy Policy or wish to make a request regarding your PII, please contact us at any of the following:

**_TELEPHONE_**

| 

**_FAX_**

| 

**_MAIL_**

| 

**_EMAIL _ ****_ _ **

|   
---|---|---|---|---  
  
+1 (608) 831-4116   
Toll-free: 1-800-688-4116 

| 

+1 (608) 836-1736 

| 

Attn: Privacy   
Electronic Theatre Controls, Inc   
3031 Pleasant View Rd.   
Middleton, WI 53562, USA 

| 

  * 

  * #### Or by filling out the below contact form:

Name: 

Email: 

Comments:  

  *     * **Third Party Contact Information:**

BigCommerce, Inc.   
11305 Four Points   
Austin, TX 78726   
Attention: General Counsel

Robly Digital Marketing LLC   
(855-557-6259)   
http://support.robly.com/contact-form/

Web Courseworks, Ltd.   
7617 Mineral Point Road #301   
Madison, WI 53717

Cvent   
8180 Greensboro Drive, Suite 900   
McLean, VA 22102

MindTouch   
San Diego, CA 92101   
www.mindtouch.com

* * *

###### 

  * #### **_Cookie Policy (not the good kind)_**

_Last update: September 4, 2019_

This Cookie Policy explains what cookies are and how we (Electronic Theatre Controls, Inc., and its affiliates) use them. Please read this Cookie Policy carefully to understand our policies and practices regarding the information we collect using cookies and how we use and share that information. We strive to keep this policy up to date, but we cannot guarantee its accuracy at all times. In addition, we may update this Cookie Policy from time to time. 

###### **What are cookies?**

"Cookies" are pieces of information that a website sends to your computer while you are viewing that website. We may set and access the cookies listed below on your computer to track and store preferential information about you. Please note that most Internet browsers will allow you to stop cookies from being stored on your computer and to delete cookies stored on your computer. If you do not wish us to collect cookies, you may set your browser to refuse cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being sent. If you do so, please note that some parts of this Site may then be inaccessible or may not function properly. If you are located in the European Union, you can use our cookie control tool to turn off certain cookies. Please see below for directions on how to use our cookie control tool. 

###### **Types of cookies**   

    * **Essential Cookies.** Essential cookies are required in order to make our site run. These cookies run automatically when you visit our site and cannot be turned off. Without these cookies, our site would not work as it should. Below is a list of the essential cookies used on each of our sites:

**_Cookie_** |  **_Purpose_** |  **_Domain_**  
---|---|---  
CookieControl  |  Used to store the user's preferences regarding cookie choices  |  etcconnect.com; eldg.etcconnect.com; community.etcconnect.com; support.etcconnect.com; learning.etcconnect.com; courses.etcconnect.com; blog.etcconnect.com; shop.etcconnect.com; shop.etcconnect.com; etcselect.etcconnect.com   
.ASPXAuth  |  Determines if a user is authenticated  |  etcconnect.com   
ASP.NET_SessionId  |  Allows a user’s preferences to be displayed throughout the user’s visit to the site. This cookie expires when you close your browser.  |  etcconnect.com   
csAuthenticatedUser  |  Stores user information to allow for sign-in to ETC forums  |  etcconnect.com; community.etcconnect.com; learning.etcconnect.com   
ecm  |  Stores information about the anonymous and logged in visitor, including language, currency, user culture, and site information. For authenticated users, the user id and a unique ID are stored, and compared with the values on the server to determine valid authentication.  |  etcconnect.com   
EktGUID  |  Tracks visitors to the site  |  etcconnect.com   
myetcUser  |  Allows users to stay logged into MyETC  |  etcconnect.com   
SiteLanguage  |  Stores user’s site language preference  |  etcconnect.com   
SiteRegion  |  Stores user’s site region preference  |  etcconnect.com   
vsid; __cfduid  |  Controls the chat function in MyETC  |  etcconnect.com   
.te.dpr  |  Resizes images for high-resolution displays  |  community.etcconnect.com   
.te.w  |  Stores the device width  |  community.etcconnect.com   
AuthorizationCookie  |  A Globally Unique Identifier used for security purposes  |  community.etcconnect.com   
mtwebsession; dekisession; MoodleSession  |  Maintains session state  |  support.etcconnect.com   
authtoken  |  Verifies access to portions of the site  |  support.etcconnect.com   
Frontend  |  Records session ID on the server  |  courses.etcconnect.com   
external_no_cache  |  A flag, which indicates whether caching is disabled  |  courses.etcconnect.com   
sockem_cookie  |  Maintains session state  |  blog.etcconnect.com   
Big Commerce Cookies (SHOP_TOKEN; STORE_VISITOR; SHOP_SESSION_TOKEN; fornax_anonymousId; lastVisitedCategory; __atuvc; __atuvs; bt2; di2; loc; na_id; ouid; uid; um; vc)  |  Allow customer to make purchases through site. For details please visit: https://www.bigcommerce.com/privacy/  |  shop.etcconnect.com   
JSESSIONID  |  Maintains session state  |  etcselect.etcconnect.com   
  
    * **Non-essential Cookies** : Non–essential cookies are cookies we have added to the site in order to enhance your experience on the site. You can choose to allow or disallow these cookies to run on the site, as explained below. Please note, if you block non – essential cookies, your experience on the site may be affected. Below is a list of the non–essential cookies used on each of our sites:

_**Cookie**_ |  _**Purpose**_ |  _**Domain**_ |  _**Category**_  
---|---|---|---  
Google Universal Analytics (_ga; _gat; _gid; _utma; _utmb; __utmc; __utmt; __utmz)  | Calculates visitor, session, campaign data, and site usage based on anonymous data complied into an analytics report, which we use to improve the site. For additional information, please visit: https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245  |  etcconnect.com; eldg.etcconnect.com; community.etcconnect.com; support.etcconnect.com; learning.etcconnect.com; blog.etcconnect.com; shop.etcconnect.com;  |  Analytics   
Facebook (fr; ­fbp)  | Targeted advertising. For additional information, please visit: https://www.facebook.com/policy/cookies/  | etcconnect.com; eldg.etcconnect.com; community.etcconnect.com; support.etcconnect.com;  |  Marketing   
  
    * **Third-Party Cookies.** Third-Party cookies are served by third-parties. We do not control these Third-Party cookies. If you have any questions about these Third-Party cookies, you should contact the Third-Party directly. Below is a list of the Third-Party cookies used on each of our sites:‌

**_Cookie_** |  **_Purpose_** |  **_Domain_**  
---|---|---  
Facebook (_fbc; presence; xs; c_user; sb; datr)  |  Improve the functionality of Facebook. For details, please visit: <https://www.facebook.com/policy/cookies/> |  etcconnect.com   
_pinterest_cm  |  Allows users to share pictures via Pinterest. For details please visit: https://policy.pinterest.com/en/cookies  |  blog.etcconnect.com   
Google Analytics (1P_JAR; NID)  |  Google targeted advertising. For details please visit: https://policies.google.com/technologies/cookies?hl=en-US  |  blog.etcconnect.com   
  
**Controlling Cookies**

**Essential Cookies** are required for the site to function and cannot be turned off.

**Non – essential Cookies:**

        * If you are visiting the site from within the European Union, non-essential cookies can be turned on or off by clicking on the “C” icon in the lower right hand corner of the site and changing the toggle to on or off. Non – essential cookies will not run until and unless you consent to the non – essential cookies. Your consent or non-consent will be stored for one year. After this time, or if we add a new cookie in the meantime, you will again be asked for your consent before any non – essential cookie will run. You can change your consent at any time by clicking on the “C” icon and changing the toggle to on or off.
        * If you are visiting the site from outside of the European Union, non – essential cookies will run automatically. You may be able to turn these cookies off through your browser.
        * For all visitors to any of the sites listed in the charts above, your cookie preferences for one site will be carried through to all sites.

###### **Contact Information**

If you have questions or concerns about this Cookie Policy, please contact us at any of the following:

**_TELEPHONE_**

| 

**_FAX_**

| 

**_MAIL_**

| 

**_EMAIL_**  
  
---|---|---|---  
|  | 

Attn: Legal Department   
Electronic Theatre Controls, Inc.   
3031 Pleasant View Rd.   
Middleton, WI 53562, USA 

| 

* * *

###### 

  * ##### **_Terms of Use Policy_**

Last updated: October 22, 2019

These Terms of Use (“ **Terms** ”) govern your access to and use of this website (“ **Site** ”), made available to you by Electronic Theatre Controls, Inc. (“ **ETC** ,” “ **we** ,” “ **us** ,” or “ **our** ”).

**By accessing or using the Site, you agree on behalf of yourself and any company that you represent (together, “you”) that you have read and understand these Terms and ourPrivacy Policy. **

**If you do not agree with these Terms or ourPrivacy Policy, please do not access or use the Site. **

**We reserve the right to modify these Terms at any time. All changes will be effective immediately upon posting to the Site and, by accessing or using the Site after changes are posted, you agree to those changes. Material changes will be conspicuously posted on the Site.**

    1. **Privacy Policy.** We may collect certain information from your use of the Site as set forth in our Privacy Policy, which is incorporated into these Terms by this reference. By using the Site, you agree on behalf of yourself and any company that you represent (together, “you” and “your”) to the Privacy Policy.
    2. **Intellectual Property Rights.** The Site, including its text, audio, video, graphics, charts, photographs, interfaces, icons, other content, software, computer code, data, trademarks, logos, slogans, names of products and services, documentation, other components, and the design, selection, and arrangement of content is exclusively the property of ETC or, as applicable, its suppliers and licensors, and is protected by copyright, trademark, and other intellectual property laws. Any unauthorized use of any trademarks, trade dress, or any other intellectual property belonging to ETC or any third party is strictly prohibited and may be prosecuted to the fullest extent of the law. The Site may contain references to third-party marks and copies of third-party copyrighted materials, which are the property of their respective owners.
    3. **Use of the Site; Compliance with Laws.** You may download and print one copy of the Site’s visible content for your internal use, provided you do not modify or delete any copyright, trademark, or other proprietary notices. You may not otherwise copy, reproduce, display, duplicate, sell, publish, post, license, distribute, or create derivative works of the Site or any part of the Site without the prior written consent of ETC. You may not use the Site for unlawful purposes. You may not access, use, or copy any portion of the Site or its content through the use of indexing agents, spiders, scrapers, bots, web crawlers, or other automated devices or mechanisms. You may not use the Site to post or transmit any material that contains any viruses, Trojan horses, worms, time bombs, cancelbots, malware, adware, or other computer programming routines that may damage, interfere with, surreptitiously intercept, or expropriate any system, data, or personal information. User activities that aim to render the Site or associated services inoperable or to make their use more difficult are strictly prohibited. You may not submit inaccurate information via the Site, commit fraud or falsify information in connection with your use of the Site, or act maliciously against the business interests or reputation of ETC. You are responsible for complying with all local, state, and federal laws and regulations that apply to your use of the Site.
    4. **Product Availability.** The prices and availability of products made available on the Site may change at any time without notice to you. Prices remain valid while they are listed and offered on the Site. Prices will be as posted on the Site as of the date and time of your order, as applicable. Availability of products may be limited. Some products may not be available in certain areas. All orders placed through the Site are subject to the applicable terms and policies of our third-party payment processor.
    5. **Your Account.** If you choose to set up an online account through the Site, you will be required to submit certain information in order to set up your account and will be required to establish a username and password. You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of any information you use in connection with the Site, including your username and any password. In connection with your access and use of the Site and that of any person authorized by you to access and use the Site, you are responsible for complying with all applicable laws, regulations, and policies of all relevant jurisdictions, including all applicable local rules regarding online conduct. You warrant that all information you provide to us in connection with your access to and use of the Site is true, accurate, and complete to the best of your knowledge and belief. ETC reserves the right, in its sole discretion, to terminate your use of the Site for any reason without notice or liability, including the unauthorized use of a username or password and breach of these Terms.
    6. **Copyright Policy.** We respect the intellectual property rights of others and we ask that our users do the same. In accordance with the Digital Millennium Copyright Act (“ **DMCA** ”), located at 17 U.S.C. § 512, and other applicable laws, we strive to expeditiously remove any infringing material from the Site if we become aware of the same. If you believe that anything on the Site infringes any copyright that you own or control, please provide our designated agent with a notice that contains the following information:
    * A description of the copyrighted work(s) that you claim have been infringed;
    * A description of the allegedly infringing material, including its location on the Site;
    * A statement by you that you have a good faith belief that the disputed use is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law;
    * Your email address, telephone number, and mailing address;
    * A statement by you, made under penalty of perjury, that the above information in your notice is accurate and that you are the copyright owner or are authorized to act on the copyright owner’s behalf; and
    * An electronic or physical signature of a person authorized to act on behalf of the copyright owner.
    7. **User Generated Content.**
      * The Site may allow you to create, post, or otherwise submit comments, images, data, text, and other content via the Site and to respond to content submitted by others (together, **“User Generated Content”** ), for example, via the Forum. User Generated Content is neither generated nor controlled by ETC. ETC is not responsible for any User Generated Content. You are responsible for all User Generated Content that you submit and for the legality, originality, and appropriateness thereof. You must comply with our Acceptable Use Policy, below, when submitting User Generated Content. By submitting User Generated Content you warrant that you have the rights, permissions, and consents necessary to submit such User Generated Content and to authorize us to use such User Generated Content as permitted by these Terms. You further warrant that User Generated Content you submit will not cause ETC to violate any law regulation. By submitting User Generated Content, you waive any right, and you agree not to assert, that any use of such User Generated Content by us or any third party infringes or violates your intellectual property rights, rights of privacy, rights of publicity, or other right. You retain any copyright or other intellectual property right you may have in User Generated Content that you submit.
      * User Generated Content is not monitored. ETC reserves the right, but does not have the obligation, to review User Generated Content and its submission. ETC also reserves the right, but does not have the obligation, to delete User Generated Content from the Site at any time for any reason (including without limitation deletion due to violation of our Acceptable Use Policy). ETC has no obligation to archive or otherwise store any User Generated Content. ETC reserves the right to impose limits on Site features (e.g., the ability to submit User Generated Content) and to restrict your access to all or parts of the Site at any time for any reason, including without limitation violation of our Acceptable Use Policy.
      * If you submit User Generated Content, you grant ETC a perpetual, irrevocable, transferable, assignable, sublicensable, royalty-free, fully paid-up, worldwide license to use, copy, reproduce, modify, adapt, reformat, translate, excerpt, prepare derivative works of, store, publish, publicly perform, publicly display, distribute, license, sell, and exploit for any purpose, including without limitation developing, manufacturing, and marketing products and services. For more information on how we use and share User Generated Content, please review our Privacy Policy.
    8. **NO WARRANTY.** THE SITE IS PROVIDED “AS IS,” “AS AVAILABLE,” AND WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY OF ANY KIND. ETC MAKES COMMERCIALLY REASONABLE EFFORTS TO ENSURE THAT ALL MATERIAL, INFORMATION, AND DATA ON THE SITE (EXCLUDING USER GENERATED CONTENT) IS ACCURATE AND RELIABLE, BUT ACCURACY CANNOT BE GUARANTEED. ETC DOES NOT GUARANTEE THE QUALITY, COMPLETENESS, TIMELINESS, OR AVAILABILITY OF THE SITE. ETC DOES NOT WARRANT THAT THE SITE WILL BE UNINTERRUPTED OR ERROR-FREE, THAT ANY DEFECTS IN THE SITE WILL BE CORRECTED, OR THAT THE SITE OR THE SERVERS THAT MAKE THE SITE AVAILABLE ARE FREE OF VIRUSES OR OTHER HARMFUL CONDITIONS OR COMPONENTS. ETC IS NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR ANY TYPOGRAPHICAL ERRORS ON THE SITE. TO THE MAXIMUM EXTENT PERMITTED BY LAW, ETC EXPRESSLY DISCLAIMS ALL WARRANTIES OF ANY KIND WITH RESPECT TO THE SITE, INCLUDING WITHOUT LIMITATION THOSE REGARDING AVAILABILITY, QUALITY, ACCURACY, MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR ANY USE OR PURPOSE, COMPATIBILITY WITH ANY STANDARDS OR USER REQUIREMENTS, TITLE, AND NONINFRINGEMENT. ETC HAS NO RESPONSIBILITY FOR THE TIMELINESS, DELETION, MISDELIVERY, OR FAILURE TO STORE ANY USER COMMUNICATION. 

YOUR USE OF THE SITE IS AT YOUR OWN RISK AND YOU, ALONE, ARE RESPONSIBLE FOR ANY DAMAGE TO YOUR COMPUTER HARDWARE, SOFTWARE, SYSTEMS, AND NETWORKS, ANY LOSS OF DATA THAT RESULTS FROM THE DOWNLOAD OF ANY INFORMATION FROM THE SITE, AND FOR ANY OTHER DAMAGE THAT MAY BE INCURRED. WE MAKE NO REPRESENTATION THAT THE SITE IS APPROPRIATE OR AVAILABLE FOR USE IN LOCATIONS OTHER THAN THE UNITED STATES. IF YOU CHOOSE TO ACCESS THE SITE FROM LOCATIONS OTHER THAN THE UNITED STATES, YOU DO SO AT YOUR OWN RISK AND YOU ARE RESPONSIBLE FOR COMPLYING WITH APPLICABLE LAWS AND REGULATIONS. NO ADVICE OR INFORMATION, ORAL OR WRITTEN, OBTAINED BY YOU FROM ETC OR IN ANY MANNER FROM THE SITE CREATES ANY WARRANTY.

    9. **NO LIABILITY.** TO THE EXTENT PERMITTED BY LAW, IN NO EVENT WILL ETC, ITS AFFILIATES, OR ITS OR THEIR RESPECTIVE DIRECTORS, OFFICERS, EMPLOYEES, REPRESENTATIVES, CONSULTANTS, AGENTS, SUPPLIERS, OR LICENSORS BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL, EXEMPLARY, PUNITIVE, OR CONSEQUENTIAL LOSS OR DAMAGE, OR ANY OTHER LOSS OR DAMAGE OF ANY KIND, ARISING OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SITE OR YOUR USE OF THE SITE (INCLUDING WITHOUT LIMITATION THE INPUT OF PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE AND OTHER INFORMATION INTO THE SITE), WHETHER THE CLAIM IS BASED IN CONTRACT, TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE), STRICT LIABILITY, WARRANTY, OR OTHERWISE, AND EVEN IF ETC HAS EXPRESS KNOWLEDGE OF THE POSSIBILITY OF THE LOSS OR DAMAGE. YOUR SOLE AND EXCLUSIVE REMEDY IS TO STOP ACCESSING AND USING THE SITE. WITHOUT LIMITING THE FOREGOING, IN NO EVENT WILL ETC’S LIABILITY TO YOU EXCEED $100, EVEN IF THIS REMEDY FAILS OF ITS ESSENTIAL PURPOSE. SOME JURISDICTIONS DO NOT ALLOW THE EXCLUSION OR LIMITATION OF CERTAIN DAMAGES, SO SOME OF THE ABOVE EXCLUSIONS AND LIMITATIONS MAY NOT APPLY TO YOU.
    10. **Indemnification.** You will indemnify, defend, and hold harmless ETC, its affiliates, and its and their respective directors, officers, employees, representatives, consultants, agents, suppliers, and licensors from and against all losses, claims, liabilities, demands, complaints, actions, damages, judgments, settlements, fines, penalties, damages, expenses, and costs (including without limitation reasonable attorneys’ fees) that arise out of or in connection with your access to or use of the Site, your misuse of any material, data, or other information downloaded or otherwise obtained from the Site, your submission of User Generated Content, your order of products through the Site, or your violation of these Terms. We reserve, and you grant to us, the exclusive right to assume the defense and control of any matter subject to indemnification by you.
    11. **Third-Party Websites.** The Site may link to, or be linked to, websites not maintained or controlled by ETC. Those links are provided as a convenience and ETC is not responsible for examining or evaluating the content or accuracy of, and does not warrant or endorse, any third-party website or any products or services made available through those websites. Please take care when leaving the Site to visit a third-party website. You should read the terms of use and privacy policy for each website that you visit.
    12. **Feedback.** ETC welcomes comments regarding the Site. If you submit comments or feedback to us regarding the Site, they will not be considered or maintained as confidential, except for any Personally Identifiable Information (PII) which may be included in the comments or feedback. We may use any comments and feedback that you send us in our discretion and without attribution or compensation to you.
    13. **Disputes.** These Terms are governed by the laws of the state of Wisconsin, without regards for its conflict of law principles. Venue is exclusively in the state or federal courts, as applicable, with jurisdiction over Dane County, Wisconsin, with respect to any dispute arising under these Terms unless otherwise determined by ETC in its sole discretion and the parties expressly agree to the exclusive jurisdiction of such courts. If there is a dispute, the prevailing party will be entitled to recovery of its costs and expenses, including reasonable attorneys’ fees. The United Nations Convention for the International Sale of Goods does not apply. Any cause of action or other claim with respect to the Site must be commenced within one year after the cause of action or claim arises.
    14. **Assignment.** We may assign our rights and delegate our duties under these Terms at any time to any party without notice to you. You may not assign these Terms without our prior written consent.
    15. **Third-Party Beneficiaries.** These Terms do not confer any rights, remedies, or benefits upon any person other than you, except that our affiliates are third-party beneficiaries of these Terms.
    16. **Interpretation.** These Terms, including our Privacy Policy and Acceptable Use Policy, are the entire agreement between you and ETC with respect to your access to and use of the Site. ETC’s failure to enforce any provision in these Terms will not constitute a waiver of that provision or any other provision. Any waiver of any provision of these Terms will be effective only if in writing and signed by ETC. If any provision of these Terms is held invalid, void, or unenforceable, that provision will be considered severable from the remaining provisions and the remaining provisions will remain in full force and effect. The headings in these Terms are for convenience only and do not affect the interpretation of these Terms. These Terms will inure to the benefit of ETC’s successors and assigns.
    17. **Survival.** Any provisions of these Terms that are intended to survive termination (including any provisions regarding indemnification or limitation of our liability) will continue in effect beyond any termination of these Terms or of your access to the Site.
    18. **Electronic Communications.** These Terms and any other documentation, agreements, notices, or communications between you and ETC may be provided to you electronically to the extent permissible by law. Please print or otherwise save a copy of all documentation, agreements, notices, and other communications for your reference.
    19. **Contact Us.** Please direct any questions and concerns regarding these Terms to us at any of the following:

**_TELEPHONE_**

| 

**_FAX_**

| 

**_MAIL_**

| 

**_EMAIL _ ****_ _ **

|   
---|---|---|---|---  
  
+1 (608) 831-4116 

| 

+1 (608) 836-1736 

| 

Attn: Webmaster   
Electronic Theatre Controls, Inc   
3031 Pleasant View Rd.   
Middleton, WI 53562, USA 

| 

* * *

###### 

  * #### **_Acceptable Use Policy_**

Last updated: October 22, 2019

By submitting creating, posting, or otherwise submitting comments, images, data, text, or other content via this website (“ **Site** ”), or by responding to content submitted by others (together, “ **User Generated Content** ”), you agree to this Acceptable Use Policy (“ **AUP** ”).

**If you do not agree with this AUP, please do not submit User Generated Content via the Site. This AUP is incorporated into and made a part of ourTerms of Use.**

**We reserve the right to modify this AUP at any time. All changes will be effective immediately upon posting to the Site and, by accessing or using the Site after changes are posted, you agree to those changes.**

    1. You must maintain a polite, pleasant, and respectful environment.
    2. You will not attack other Site users. User Generated Content that harasses, abuses, stalks, threatens, or otherwise violates the legal rights of others (such as the rights of privacy and publicity) is prohibited.
    3. User Generated Content must be relevant to the stated topic (for example, the applicable forum post).
    4. User Generated Content that is defamatory, indecent, pornographic, obscene, or otherwise objectionable is prohibited. Slurs and commentary against social, racial, religious, ethnic, and sexual orientation groups are prohibited.
    5. User Generated Content must not contain or consist of surveys, contests, pyramid schemes, chain letters, junk mail, unauthorized emails, offers to buy or sell goods or services, advertisements, or commercial solicitations, nor may User Generated Content engage in, facilitate, or encourage any of the foregoing or any illegal activities.
    6. You may not harvest or otherwise collect information about others (including without limitation email addresses).
    7. You must have the rights, permissions, and consents necessary to submit the applicable User Generated Content. For example, you may not submit any User Generated Content that contains or consists of text, images, videos, recordings, or other material that is protected by intellectual property laws and owned by another person unless you have the legal right to submit that User Generated Content.
    8. User Generated Content that contains viruses, Trojan horses, worms, time bombs, cancelbots, corrupted files, malicious code, or other software or programs that may damage a person’s software or hardware is prohibited.
    9. You may not falsify or delete any copyright management information, such as author attributions, copyright notices, legal notices, or other proprietary designations, notices, or labels concerning the origin or source of the submitted User Generated Content.
    10. You may not download User Generated Content submitted by another Site user if you know or reasonably should know that such User Generated Content cannot be legally copied, reproduced, displayed, performed, or distributed in such manner.
    11. You may not interfere, restrict, or inhibit another user’s access to or use of the Site or its features.
    12. You may not create a false identity, hide your true identity, or impersonate or represent any person other than yourself.

**AUP Violations.** Your violation of this AUP or any other provision of our Terms of Use may result in the immediate suspension of your access to the Site or its features without notice to you. ETC reserves the right to impose limits on Site features (for example, the ability to submit User Generated Content) or restrict your access to all or parts of the Site at any time for any reason, including without limitation your violation of this AUP.

**Contact Us.** Please direct any questions and concerns regarding this AUP or User Generated Content to us at the contact information below. Please do not direct questions, complaints, or other comments regarding User Generated Content to other Site users. As ETC does not monitor or review User Generated Content, we cannot address your concerns unless you send them to us.

**_TELEPHONE_**

| 

**_FAX_**

| 

**_MAIL_**

| 

**_EMAIL _ ****_ _ **

|   
---|---|---|---|---  
  
+1 (608) 831-4116 

| 

+1 (608) 836-1736 

| 

Attn: Webmaster   
Electronic Theatre Controls, Inc   
3031 Pleasant View Rd.   
Middleton, WI 53562, USA 

|
